thank you for for the kind introduction
so I'll give you our start with giving
an a background on the company I have
this slide I was giving this
presentation in Montreal to a bunch of
international students and they fought
Mon your life it's a bicycle company
because all the bikes in Montreal are
sponsored by Mon your life so we're not
a bicycle company where we're insurance
company and we we've been around for a
hundred more than a hundred years and
also we've been around for a hundred
years or more in Asia so that's quite
quite interesting in terms of where we
derive our income it mostly comes it's
kind of divided between US Canada and in
Asia is divided equally in terms of
businesses that we that we that we do we
do all the sexy stuff and financial
service or Insurance Group benefits and
investments now okay so how we how we
actually apply ai within within Manulife
so there's around 120 data scientists
within within the company around 30
percent our PhDs so we are lower than
layer six I think I calculated down 38%
so I think we should hire some PhDs from
layer six that'll be the right strategy
and we apply AI across the whole company
so it's not that we apply a I you know
just an investment or maybe just in
underwriting we apply it across
marketing finance HR really everywhere
and one cool thing that we do is that we
set up center of expertise if they're if
we find a certain subject to be
important to our strategic goals and
examples will include the natural range
processing so that's something that is
done in my team but also we have one for
graph analytics for claims and for fraud
detection we're well integrated within
the AI ecosystem in Canada so we're
partners with vector obviously but also
with Miller and Waterloo AI in the next
slide I'm going to give you a kind
a brief introduction into three use
cases of the problems do we work on I
will not go to into too much detail I
don't want to get chased from the stage
by our legal department but you'll get
an idea of what what do we do that I
guess my main messages so in in my team
there's on 20 people and we have around
40 projects and at a whole company level
we probably have 200 different AI
related projects so it's a really big
initiative really transport
transformative initiative for our
company okay so every single AI or
machine learning presentation needs for
detection and I'll tell I'll tell you
the secret why and the reason is
historically fraud detection worked
either through random sampling so you
randomly sample transactions who
investigate all through a rule-based
model so let's say all the transaction
higher than $10,000 will be investigated
and because you had already existing
business process - hi - Oh to verify a
list of transactions when data
scientists came over what they did they
just said okay we're going to give you a
better list and we're going to use our
techniques which are which worked really
well to give you a better list so we
integrated really well into existing
processes and that's one of the reasons
why fraud detection has been so
successful with with AI in our case we
apply for detection - among other things
- transactions that originated online
the way we do it we would we would build
a profile of your online activity so we
would calculate from where you connect
what's the distance between your logins
we would look at what times how you know
how quickly you move your mouse around
your screen and then we would apply a
anomaly detection model and based on
that we would find transactions that are
anomalous and with those transaction
we'll go into the investigation the
second use case is one of anti money
laundering and this is more of a use
case of graph analytics
and when you think about anti money
laundering or money laundering in
general you're probably saying you know
El Chapo and a hundred million dollars
in cash in his basement but the problem
is way more common than than you think
so imagine that you imagine a small
restaurant or small grocery shop where
someone takes cash and doesn't give you
a receipt so probably what they might be
doing they might be trying to avoid
sales tax and they end up with a bunch
of cash and what do they do they want to
now buy let's say a car or a house with
it they need to somehow put it into the
financial system the key because you
can't really pay you know half a million
dollars for for a condo with cash so
what they will do they will try to put
that money into the system but somehow
obfuscate the way it's going to end up
in their account so here you have an
example of such a scenario so on the
left-hand side you have two folks for
which a rule-based system I generated a
STR suspicion transaction report so the
reason why it was generated
they had a large large withdrawals let's
say they tried to withdraw 100k
now when analyst starts to analyze a
case like this what they will do they
will start to try to connect the dots
where did that money came from so there
was they will try to look for same phone
numbers same home address that may
connect that people to some other folks
and they will find a group of people on
the right-hand side so you have three
more people connected to a phone number
connected to a home address connected to
a joint account which is in green and
once you continue to build up the that
community you also find transactions
where the money is coming in on the into
those account because their joint then
it can go into the other accounts and
you have kind of a circle very often the
people on the right hand side they never
exist they are created using effect IDs
and they share the address because you
would want to verify that we need to
provide a real address to verify certain
documents
to receive phone calls from the bank why
this is relevant for AI and machine
learning because what do we do we would
build it for every single transaction
for every single customer so imagine we
build it in real time for hundreds of
thousands of people for probably
millions of transactions and we would
run those community detection first
algorithms to find the groups of people
and then we'll look for circles where
that money makes it makes a circle
within the financial system and that
might be a potential money-laundering
scheme okay the final the final use case
I'll be I'll talk a bit more about this
one is on call center so in a call
center you probably find it funny but
the last thing you want to get our phone
calls because the phone calls are
expensive you have to hire people to
take them and people when they're
calling their privy are probably already
upset so this is not a great customer
service so there's a lot of initiatives
within the call center to reduce the
number of calls you are getting and I'll
kind of give you an idea how a data
science projects comes around in a
setting like a call center so typically
the business will come to us and they
will you know come up with the problem
because we have 30% PhDs we'll come up
with a really smart answer which
business will typically not like and we
will then come up with something better
like transcribing the calls so in our
case we would transcribe every single
call and and we will try to look for
call reasons within those calls so when
you start thinking about this problem
you quickly realize it's it's quite
difficult so what you'll find is there's
a high noise to information ratio so
imagine that our website is down and
that word that sentence the website is
down is only going to be mentioned once
in a 20 minute conversation because
there is authentication there is a
discussion what that person wanted to do
on the website but couldn't but the
actual reason is a very short
sentence within a big chunk of your
formation so that's one problem there
are hundreds of cold reasons why people
call because typically we get millions
of calls per year and we even would then
want to call there will be multiple
reasons because you call to change your
address then you change your you know
you want to change your phone number
maybe change what you're paying for and
finally the translation are not perfect
so we're using state of the art tools
from from Amazon to transcribe our calls
but you know when a guy like me calls
with a name like mine even Amazon will
not be able to get it correctly so once
we have the data will massage it as as
mentioned previously will remove you
know all the short calls because they
would not have enough information we'll
do all this standard kind of NLP
cleaning and we'll go into modeling and
now with with the call center what you
could quickly realize at the level of
call center you cannot get any insights
because just too many calls
there is effects of seasonality as new
products we're launching we might be
sending some mail to people which will
cause a spike in cost you will not get
anything so what we did in this
particular project we start to
categorize the calls before doing any
analysis so the way we'd categorize we
would first do it by line of business so
let's say live insurance in our case
then buy a product in our case that's
vitality and finally at the last level
we'll do it at the level of any issue so
that would be a registration issue or a
website issue what is cool about this
that then you can track all those
reasons call reasons at the granular
level so you can tell how many
registration issues there are per month
for vitality and what is the NPS which
is the customer satisfaction score
within those calls you can prioritize
your work based on the NPS so you you
will try to fix the
or target the reasons that lead to the
worse worse calls once you are in the
small buckets you have maybe 2,000 3,000
calls in those then you run your topic
modeling your your NLP algorithms on top
of that and then you get your insights
and you go to the business and you
propose some changes so you tell them
you know if you let's say fix issues
with your website you'll be able to
produce the number of course by let's
say a few thousand a month which will
save you X amount of dollars what is
what is good regarding the that
classification we did categorization of
the cost is then in three months once
business does it you can then look okay
what was the impact of that because
you're tracking this every month and
again at the level of call center calls
might be going you know everywhere
because because of all the seasonality
and other stuff and this kind of a
concludes what I want to say obviously I
came here partially for for hiring
reasons so we're hiring for a bunch of
positions if you if you're interested
and this is the picture from our
headquarters or younger blur and you
know the people say that grass is not
always greener on the other side but I
think our grass is pretty green thank
you